Fine Arts Federation of New York
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, circa 1914-2004, bulk 1930s-1960s, Series 4:; (Boxes 9-12; 2.75 linear feet)
  - Constituent Societies (Box 10)
    - Groupe Americain Societe des Architectes Diplomes par le Gouvernment, 1935-1941 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - The Municipal Art Society, 1916-1967 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - National Academy of Design, 1935-1951 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - National Association of Women Artists, 1941-1956 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - National Institute for Architectural Education, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - National Sculpture Society, 1935-1947 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - National Society of Mural Painters, 1931-1951, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - New York Chapter of the American Institute of Architects, 1935-1948, 1962-1967 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - New York Chapter of the American Society of Landscape Architects, 1935-1942 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - New York State Chapter of the American Artists Professional League, 1931-1957 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - New York Watercolor Club, 1935-1938 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Society of American Artists, 1937-1941 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Society of Beaux Arts Architects, 1937-1945 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Westchester County Society of Architects, 1935-1945 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Special Committees, Various, 1936-1938 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Special Committees - Permanent (Box 10)
    - Art Commission, 1929-1955, 1965-1966, 1983-1989, 1999-2000, (4 folders) (Box 10, Folder 30-33)
    - Art Commission Associates, 1932-1942 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Committee of Nine - Mayor's Panel of Architects, 1943-1947, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Nominations to the Art Commission, 1934-1950, 1964-1966, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 36-38)
  - Special Committees - Projects (Box 10)
    - American Artists Congress, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - A.S. Bard Award Dinner, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Battery Park Design Competition, 1941-1945, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 41-42)
  - Special Committees - Projects (Box 11)
    - Battery Park Design Competition, 1941-1945, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Billboards, Outdoor Advertising and Skyline Signs, 1939-1948, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn Battery Bridge, 1939-1941, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
    - East River Drive - Asphalt Plant, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Fort Tryon Park, 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Library Records, 1935-1942 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - George McAneny and Stanley Isaacs Award, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art Proposed Extension, 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Monuments [Clippings], 1920s, 1943, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
    - Monuments in New York, circa 1914-1928, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - New York City Charter, 1936-1938 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - New York Public Library Flag Pole, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - New York State War Memorial, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - New York Worlds Fair 1939, 1935-1940 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Nightingale American Hospital, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Carl Schurz Memorial, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Seal, 1937-1941 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - State Planning, 1942-1944 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - I.N. Phelps Stokes Award Dinner, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - War Memorials, 1943-1947 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - War Posters, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - WPA Adult Education and Writers Project, 1937-1941 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Special Committees - Temporary (Box 11)
    - Committee for Restoration of the State Fine Arts Commission, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Committee on Government and Art, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Committee on Public Relations, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Committee to Confer With Mayor, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Committee to Take Up the Question of a Fine Arts Secretary, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Minute Men Committee, 1935, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - National Art Council for Defense, 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Vigilance Committee on Legislation, 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Standing Committees, Various, 1935-1950, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 33-34)
  - Standing Committees (Box 11)
    - Admissions, 1926-1956 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Architecture, 1935-1937, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - City Development, 1927-1961, (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 37-41)
  - Standing Committees (Box 12)
    - City Development, 1927-1961 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Landscape Architecture, 1938-1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Legislation, 1924, 1933-1967, (6 folders) (Box 12, Folder 3-8)
    - Mural Painting, 1935-1947 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Painting, 1935-1950 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Parks and Public Buildings, 1929-1945, 1953-1955, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
    - Sculpture, 1935-1944, 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Statistics, 1927-1936 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Administrative Records, 1895, 1897, 1935-2005, Series 5:; (Boxes 12-14; 1.9 linear feet)
  Administrative Records include copies of the F.A.F. constitution and by-laws; revised constitutions and by-laws with accompanying correspondence and notes; meeting minutes and ancillary records; and project files from the 1980s-1990s containing printed materials, reports, and correspondence.
  - Annual Treasurers' Reports, 1978-2003 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Biographical Materials [Board Members?], circa 1987-1996 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Centennial Celebration (Apr. 19, 1995), 1994-1995, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 17-18)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, Constitution, and By-Laws, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1967, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Constitution Revisions, 1895, 1897, 1935-1967, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 21-22)
  - Historic Districts and Landmarks Preservation, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1986-1990 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Local Laws, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Meetings (Box 12)
    - Announcements for Committee and Board Meetings, 2000-2005 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Annual/Semi-Annual Meeting Attendance, 1983-1999 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1989-2005 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Minutes - Extra Copies and Drafts, 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Minutes and Attachments, 1935-1959, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 30-32)
    - Minutes and Attachments, 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Meetings (Box 13)
    - Minutes and Attachments, 1986-1995, (19 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1935-1943 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Nominations and Elections for Officers and Board of Directors, 1935-1952, 1962-1967, (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 21-23)
  - Nominations and Elections for Officers and Board of Directors, 1935-1952, 1962-1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Position Statements, 1987-1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Project Files (Box 14)
    - Brighton Beach, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Brooklyn Heights, 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Bryant Park, 1983-1985 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Casitas, 1985, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Central Park Tennis House, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - City Hall Park, circa 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Cooper Committee Report, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Inclusionary Housing Program, 1986-1987, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Manhattan West (Brodsky), 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Nehemiah/Arverne, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Penn Yards, 1987-1989 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Public Art (Percentage for Art), 1983-1991 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - South Ferry, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - UPS, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Zoning, circa 1980-1988 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Standing Committees, circa 1935-1939 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Statements and Testimonies, 1987-1989 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Printed Materials, 1971-2005, Series 6:; (Box 14; 6 folders)
  Printed Materials include scattered announcements, catalogs, clippings, and pamphlets. Additional printed material can be found interspersed throughout the collection.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Brochures and Clippings, circa 1974-1996 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Centennial Exhibition Catalog (Apr. 19, 1995), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 2002-2005 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Exhibitions, Lorrie Goulet, 1971-2000 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Michelangelo's Frescoes, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Pamphlets, Fine Arts Federation of New York, 1979, circa 1990s (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous, 1914-1966, bulk mid-1930s-1950s, Series 7:; (Boxes 14-15; 1.6 linear feet)
  This series includes folders containing various types of records with little discernable order, a mélange of correspondence, drafts, meeting minutes, mimeographs, notes, reports, scattered clippings, transcriptions, and other documents. These records were likely weeded from the records microfilmed in 1968. A handful of folders with some discernable order, or for whom the creator was able to be determined, have been filed in other series appropriate to the folder's content.
  Folders and materials within folders were not rearranged, and remain in the same order found upon processing.
  - Miscellaneous, 1914-1966, (12 folders) (Box 14, Folder 26-37)
  - Miscellaneous, 1914-1966, (23 folders) (Box 15, Folder 1-23)
- Scrapbooks, 1995, Series 8:; (Box 16; 2 folders)
  Found are two photo scrapbooks documenting two separate events held in 1995. Materials include color and black and white photographs from the event, invitations, scattered correspondence, and printed materials housed in plastic sleeves.
  Folders are arranged chronologically by event date.
  - Photo Scrapbook for F.A.F's Centennial Celebration (Apr. 19, 1995), 1995 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Photo Scrapbook for New York Artists Equity Association, Inc. Awards Dinner (Dec. 7, 1995), 1995 (Box 16, Folder 2)